farecompare.com 2019-02-02

# Privacy Policy - FareCompare

Thank you for visiting FareCompare. FareCompare values your privacy and appreciates your use of our services. FareCompare employs best practices and all reasonable efforts to protect its registered and unregistered users’ information. Our mission is to help you find the best deals on the travel you love. To do that, we will prompt you with personalized content we think you’ll be interested in based on information we collect from you and third parties. We only collect and use information where we have a legal basis for doing so.

### Information We Collect

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes your IP location to enhance your website experience and set home city, language, and currency.

We collect information on what pages users access or visit, limited user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, information volunteered by the user, such as survey information and/or site registrations. 

**1\. Unregistered Users**  
If you do not register when you visit FareCompare, the information we collect from you is limited to your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Web site and track usage statistics. All information we collect from unregistered users and is used only in aggregate and used to generate overall reports on our visitors, but is not identifiable to individual visitors.

 **2.  Registered Users**  
If you register for an account with FareCompare, FareCompare collects and saves any information you provide us or authorize us to collect, including but not limited to:  
– Personal Data: email address, password  
– Preferences: language, currency, home city and email subscriptions  
– Behavior: website and email (see below for more details on collection of cookies)

FareCompare uses this information solely for the purpose of providing you with the price alerts and travel information that you have requested. FareCompare will seek your consent in compliance with applicable law, to use this information for any other purpose.

Some cookies are necessary for account creation and session enhancements. See the explanation below of how we use cookies for more details.

FareCompare also saves travel information for trips you have signed up to watch, including origin, destination, departure date and return date.

 **Use of Cookies and Similar Technology**

We use “cookies” and/or similar technology to help you log in, personalize content and ads, to provide social media features, to analyze our traffic, and to enhance user experience. A cookie may contain information that allows us to track your path through our Website and to determine whether you have visited us before. We use cookies in this manner to help us understand how visitors use our site and to help us to improve our site. However, unless you register with us, it contains no personally identifiable information that would allow us to identify you. Cookies cannot be used to read data off of your hard drive and cannot retrieve information from any other cookies created by other Web sites. 

**Necessary cookies:** The following are cookies that we use which are necessary for Website function:

Cookie| Purpose  
---|---  
IP address| To allow us to diagnose problems with our server, administer our website, and track usage statistics. Additionally, we use IP Addresses for preference targeting or geographic information necessary for site function as well as for advertisement targeting (which is a basic function of our business). Without advertisement targeting, we would not be able to display any prices.  
Session ID| This is a proprietary cookie that allows us to understand what actions took place throughout the sessions. We also capture Device ID within the Session ID cookie so that we can determine a return user.  
Session ID tracking| This is a proprietary cookie that allows us to understand what actions took place throughout the session.  
UTM Tags for attribution| Since we work with advertisers to give you all available prices for an itinerary, we have to be able to attribute that action to an individual partner. We are not collecting personal data, just a click as part of our basic business function.  
  
 **Other Cookies:** The following cookies may be necessary for account creation and session enhancements:

 **Preferences:**

Cookie| Purpose  
---|---  
Language and Currency| We collect and store language and currency preferences to better display our site for our users when they return.  
Personal Preferences| We use some cookies to remember any personal settings like airport preferences, filters, alerts and your privacy settings.  
  
 **Marketing:**

Cookie| Purpose  
---|---  
Site Analytics| We use this to track click through behavior within an email and onto the website.  
Email Marketing| We use this as the send mechanism for emails. This inherently tracks open rates, performance, and successful email sends for billing purposes.  
Intent Media| We offer personalized shopping experiences and advertising through Intent Media, which uses online identifiers to identify visitors. To view Intent Media’s privacy policy, click here. To opt out, click here.  
  
 **Opt out of third-party advertising via Cookies:** You will have to opt-out of each device you use to access our services.

Third Party Providers| Opt Out Details  
---|---  
Facebook| You can follow the instructions for app and web/mobile web on this [page](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217).   
Google| You can opt-out on this [page](https://adssettings.google.com/).  
Bing| You can opt-out [here](https://choice.microsoft.com/).  
Yahoo| You can opt-out [here](https://policies.oath.com/us/en/oath/privacy/controls/index.html).  
Intent Media| You can set an Intent Media opt-out cookier at [here](https://intentmedia.com/opt-out/).  
Clicktripz| For more information, click [here](http://www.clicktripz.com/privacy_policy.php).  
  
 **Choosing how cookies are used on FareCompare:**  
– You may refuse to accept a cookie from us either by declining to accept (if provided the option to opt-in) or by opting-out. Note that if you decline to accept or opt-out of our use of cookies which are listed above as necessary in order to provide the service, you may not be able to use the functions of our Website.  
– Most browsers let you block “third party cookies” which are from sites other than the one you’re visiting. These vary from browser to browser, so check your browser settings for more information and follow the procedures specific to your Web browser. Although you may do so, you may find that your browser reacts strangely when visiting not only our Web site but other Web sites as well.

If you visit our site from a site operated by one of our partners, and you have registered with that partner limited information about you that you have provided to that partner may be transmitted to us. You should review the privacy policy of the Web site from which you reached our site in order to determine what information was collected and how you agreed that our partner could use that information.

### How we use your Information

The information collected from registered and unregistered users is used to provide you with a relevant experience while visiting FareCompare, as well as to deliver relevant information to you via email and other contact points you provide to FareCompare.

 **Email Communications**  
The information we collect on about you, and/or which you consent to allow us to use, is in part used to send you targeted emails, through a third party vendor, with content related to your travel interests, such as:  
– Flight prices and other information for the trip you have signed up to watch, including related deals such as hotels and rental cars for that trip  
– Targeted deals from your preferred home city  
– Recommended flights based on previous search history  
– Travel advice relevant to your home city

We track and analyze email behavior, such as opens and clicks, to:  
– Determine overall email performance  
– Decide who should be sent emails  
– Track performance of offers provided by our partners, for billing purposes

We share information about your use of our Website with our social media, advertising, and analytics partners, who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services. Such information is not personally identifiable.  
The Web Site may contain links to other websites and online services. When you link to such other sites and services (including by means of clicking on hyperlinks, logos, widgets, banners or advertisements), you become subject to their terms of use and privacy policies. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you click on a link and leave the Web Site, and to read the privacy policies of every website that collects Personal Information from you.

With your permission, we may share your information with our marketing partners and other third parties so that they may contact you directly regarding special promotions or offers. If you have consented to share your Personal Information with third parties for such third parties’ marketing purposes, you can change your mind at any time and may let us know by changing your user preferences.  
You are only sent emails for which you have provided consent, and you can unsubscribe or manage your email preferences at any time here.

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our Web site to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to consent to or decline such new uses, as required by law. We will only use your personal data as authorized by law. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web site periodically.

 **Third Party Advertising**

We allow selected third parties to advertise their goods and services on our website to better enhance your experience. These third parties may use one or more methods, including “cookies,” to collect limited information regarding your visit to our site. This limited information may include your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash® installed. The information gathered will not include your name, address, email address, or telephone number. Third parties generally use this information for geographic or preference targeting, such as showing California ads to someone in California or showing ads for particular goods or services to someone who frequents particular types of websites. You have the option as to whether or not you choose to view this advertising by clicking on the applicable third party’s ad. If you would like more information about this practice, third-party cookies, or your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

 **Your User Preferences**  
Registered users can update email preferences by clicking the update profile link in the footer of email we send. If you would like to delete your profile, you can do so by going to Account Settings.

 **How we help protect your user information**  
FareCompare has security features to help protect the personal information we collect. For example, we limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information. We also employ processes (such as password hashing, login auditing, and idle session termination) to protect against unauthorized access to your personal information. 

**Children’s Privacy**  
This website is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect information about children. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send personal information to us, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child to inform him or her that we must have parental consent before receiving his or her personal information.

 **Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time and without prior notice. We will notify you of material changes to how we use your personal information prior to implementing such changes. We may notify you about such a material change by email or prominent notice on our website. Any changes to our practices will not change our commitment to honor privacy in accordance with all applicable laws.

 **Data Request**  
If you would like to request a copy of any data we have collected about you, please submit an email to customer.service@farecompare.com from the email associated with your account and request your data. Data will be exported into a CSV file and delivered within 30 days of the request. In addition, any requests for correction or erasure of your data will be responded to promptly and in accordance with applicable laws.

 **Privacy Policy Statement**  
This is the website of FareCompare, LP.  
Our postal address is  
18111 Preston Road, Suite 800  
Dallas, TX 75252

For questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please email, please reach out to our customer service team at [customer.service@farecompare.com](mailto:customer.service@farecompare.com).
